thevictoriaadvocate.com 2019-06-23

# Privacy Policy | Site | victoriaadvocate.com

**VICTORIA ADVOCATE PRIVACY POLICY**

For each visitor to the Web site, the Victoria Advocate servers automatically collect information about which pages are visited and the domain name (for example, www.victoriaadvocate.com) of visitors. This information is used for internal review, to tailor information to individual visitors and for Web site traffic audits. We also provide this information (as well as information from third-party market researchers) about our users on an aggregated, anonymous basis to our advertisers.

The Victoria Advocate may place a "cookie" on the browser of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain any personally identifying information. A cookie may be used to tell when your computer has contacted the Web site. The Victoria Advocate uses the information for editorial purposes and for other purposes such as delivery of features and advertisements, so the Victoria Advocate can customize delivery of information to you without compromising privacy. For example, cookies may be used to ensure that you will not see the same banner advertisement too often in a single session.

Through your use of the Web site, the Victoria Advocate may collect information about you that identifies you or your household. Normally, you would provide such information when specifically asked for it by the Victoria Advocate. Any information in the Victoria Advocate's possession solely as a result of your use of the Web site and that is associated with you or your household is considered "Personal Information." It consists of both information supplied by you (e.g. name, address, telephone number and e-mail address) and information collected about how you use the Web site (e.g. the fact that you have bought merchandise through the Web site). It does not include aggregate information (e.g. the total number of household users older than 18 years, the zip code in which a user lives) or information that you have made public on the Web site or that is otherwise publicly available.

The Victoria Advocate uses personal information only for purposes necessary to provide the Web site and other products and services to you. These purposes are as follow:

to process requests or orders placed with advertisers or merchants

to perform such normal business operations as billing, collecting and accounting

to personalize and publicize the Web site based on your interests, including making you aware of editorial features, advertisements and commercial items

to investigate complaints and to protect the Web site and the Victoria Advocate, its readers and employees as provided by law or in case of emergency, as determined by legal counsel for the Victoria Advocate except as necessary to process your requests or orders placed with advertisers or merchants featured on the Web site

The Victoria Advocate does not rent, sell, barter or give away any lists containing personal information for use by any outside company. The Victoria Advocate also respects the privacy of data on your personal computer and does not access, read, upload or store data contained in or derived from your private files without your authorization.

 **LINKS**

The Victoria Advocate site contains links to other sites. The Victoria Advocate is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites, including any sites that may indicate a special relationship or partnership with the Victoria Advocate (such as co-branded pages or "powered by" or "in cooperation with" relationships). The Victoria Advocate does not disclose personally identifiable information or unique identifiers to those responsible for the linked sites. The linked sites, however, may collect personal information from you that is not subject to the Victoria Advocate's control. To ensure protection of your privacy, always review the privacy policy of the sites you may visit by linking from the Victoria Advocate site.

 **OPT OUT PROCEDURES**

You always may opt out of receiving future mailings or other information from the Victoria Advocate. If the mailing does not have an e-mail cancellation form, send e-mail to feedback@vicad.com detailing the type of information that you no longer desire to receive.

 **CHILDREN'S PRIVACY**

The following additional terms, conditions and notices apply to use of the Web site by children under the age of 13 years whenever the Victoria Advocate becomes aware that a user is in that age range:

Users under 13 years old may not submit or post information on the Web site without the consent of the user's parent or legal guardian. Prior to collecting any personal information about a child under 13, the Victoria Advocate makes reasonable efforts to obtain consent from the child's parent after informing the parent about the types of information the Victoria Advocate will collect, how it will be used, and under what circumstances it will be disclosed.

Although the Victoria Advocate will apply these children's terms and conditions whenever it becomes aware that a user who submits personal information is less than 13 years old, no method is foolproof. The Victoria Advocate strongly encourages parents and guardians to supervise their children's online activities and consider using parental control tools available from online services and software manufacturers to help provide a child-friendly online environment. These tools also can prevent children from disclosing online their name, address, and other personal information without parental permission.

"Personal Information" collected from children may include any of the information defined above as "Personal Information" with respect to general users of the Web site and may be used by the Victoria Advocate for the same purposes. Except as necessary to process a child's requests or orders placed with advertisers or merchants featured on the Web site, the Victoria Advocate does not rent, sell, barter or give away any lists containing a child's Personal Information for use by any outside company.

If a child enters a game, contest or other activity sponsored by the Victoria Advocate on the Web site, the child may be required by the Victoria Advocate to provide the minimum Personal Information reasonably necessary for the child to participate in such activity.

A child's parent or legal guardian may request the Victoria Advocate to provide a description of the Personal Information that the Victoria Advocate has collected from the child, as well as instruct the Victoria Advocate to cease further use, maintenance and collection of Personal Information from the child.

If a child voluntarily discloses his or her name, e-mail address or other personally-identifying information on chat areas, bulletin boards or other forums or public posting areas, such disclosures may result in unsolicited messages from other parties.

 **GENERAL**

These terms and conditions constitute the entire agreement and understanding between you and the Victoria Advocate with respect to use of the Web site, superseding all prior or contemporaneous communications and/or proposals. The Victoria Advocate reserves the right to make changes to these terms and conditions immediately by posting the changed terms and conditions in this location. By continuing to use the Web site, you are agreeing to all changes made by the Victoria Advocate. A printed version of these terms and conditions shall be admissible in judicial or administrative proceedings based upon or relating to use of the Web site to the same extent and subject to the same conditions as other business documents and records originally generated and maintained in printed form.

The Web site is controlled and operated by the Victoria Advocate from its principal office in Victoria, Texas, USA. The Victoria Advocate makes no representation that materials on the Web site are appropriate or available for use in other locations. Those who choose to access the Web site from other locations do so on their own initiative and are responsible for compliance with local laws, if and to the extent local laws are applicable. The Web site is not intended to subject the Victoria Advocate to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than the State of Texas and the United States of America.

 **COMMENTS ON ARTICLES**

We reserve the right to use your comments and name within editorial purposes for the Victoria Advocate. We will not share your personal information related to your user accounts in any way other than previously stated.

 **CONTACTING US**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, the practices of the Victoria Advocate, or your dealings with the Victoria Advocate, you may contact us at:

Victoria Advocate

 **Attn:** Digital Editor

311 E. Constitution St.

Victoria, Texas 77901

 **Phone:** 361-580-6519

 **Fax:** 361-574-1225

 **e-mail:** [feedback@vicad.com](mailto:feedback@vicad.com)

#### E-Edition Notification

Do you subscribe to our digital edition? If you do, be sure to subscribe to this mailing list and you'll be able to read the digital edition of our paper as early as 5am! Click [**HERE**](https://www.victoriaadvocate.com/users/admin/mailinglist/ "CLICK HERE") to sign up today!

#### News Updates

Would you like to receive our daily newsletter? Click [**HERE**](https://www.victoriaadvocate.com/users/admin/mailinglist/ "CLICK HERE") to signup today!

#### E-Edition Notification

Do you subscribe to our digital edition? If you do, be sure to subscribe to this mailing list and you'll be able to read the digital edition of our paper as early as 5am! Click [**HERE**](https://www.victoriaadvocate.com/users/admin/mailinglist/ "CLICK HERE") to sign up today!

#### News Updates

Would you like to receive our daily newsletter? Click [**HERE**](https://www.victoriaadvocate.com/users/admin/mailinglist/ "CLICK HERE") to signup today!
